<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Helpful Resources on Little Loaf Company</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Helpful Resources on Little Loaf Company</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:51:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Open Baking Sourdough</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/open-baking-sourdough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:51:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/open-baking-sourdough/</guid>
      <description>Dutch Oven vs Open Bake When starting out with sourdough the majority of bakers opt to use a dutch oven to create steam during the first part of a loafs bake. This is a wonderful method and how I did so until I needed to expand the volume of what my home kitchen could produce when I decided to start my own micro bakery. If an individual needs to make more then two loaves at a time; odds are that the need to ditch the dutch oven will become almost non negotiable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Starter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sourdough-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 16:47:16 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sourdough-starter/</guid>
      <description>What is a sourdough starter? The sourdough starter is the leavening agent that gives rise to our sourdough bread. By capturing and cultivating the wild yeast that live all around us (and on us), we can create an invaluable tool in our kitchens that will take care of you for the rest of your life.&#xA;Types of sourdough starters Based on the flavor that a baker desires in their loaves, a different type of starter may suit their needs better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Batard Recipe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sourdough-batard-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 16:37:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sourdough-batard-recipe/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 47g whole wheat flour 372g white flour, 12.5%-14.5% protein 93g sourdough starter 279g water, 95°F 9g sea salt ~5g rice flour Equipment 9” oval banneton dough card dutch oven Directions Yields one ~800g loaf of finished dough&#xA;1. Assemble the Dough Combine the whole wheat flour, white flour, and salt in a bowl. Add the sourdough starter to the water and stir to dissolve. Pour the liquid mixture into the dry ingredients and mix thoroughly until no more dry flour remains using either a hand, dough whisk, or stand mixer.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
